[treehouse]
[Website Waters, Stage 1:Website Basics, with Nick Pettit]
Hi, I'm Nick, and welcome to Website Waters.
In this first island, we're going to make our very first website.
If you have no previous experience building websites, don't worry.
We'll start at the very beginning and work our way forward.
All you need is a computer, which we'll use to type up our code.
By the end of this island,
we'll have created a complete website.
Allison went ahead and designed a mockup
of what the final site will look like.
Now it's our job to turn it into code.
This site is for a fictional bakery
called Smells Like Bakin.
Let's dive right in and try a little bit of coding.
This program that I'm going to be typing in
is called a text editor.
We'll learn more about text editing programs in upcoming videos,
but for now, just try to watch and absorb.
Let's type in the headline Smells Like Bakin.
That's great, but we'll have to identify this line
so that our web browser will know that it's a headline
and not something else, like a paragraph or an image.
To do this, we'll use special markings called tags.
Wrapping an H1 tag around the text, Smells Like Bakin,
tells the browser that this text
is a level-one header.
So we'll go ahead and type &lt;h1&gt;,
and then we'll do the same thing on the other side by typing in &lt;/h1&gt;.
Now, let's switch over to our web browser and open the page that we created.
When we refresh, we should now see
the headline that we typed.
And there it is--Smells Like Bakin.
Now you go ahead and try it.